(sonar pings)
13 metres. You should see it.
Okay. Take her up
and over the bow rail.
Okay, Mir 2, we're going over the bow.
Stay with us.
(sonar pings)
(mechanical whirring)
Okay, quiet. We're rolling.
Seeing her coming out
of the darkness like a ghost ship...
..still gets me every time.
To see the sad ruin
of the great ship sitting here...
..where she landed at 2:30
in the morning of April 15, 1912,...
..after her long fall...
..from the world above.
You are so full of shit, boss !
(mechanical whirring)
(sonar pinging)
Dive six - here we are again
on the deck of Titanic.
2 1/2 miles down, 3,821 meters.
The pressure outside
is 3 1/2 tons per square inch.
These windows are nine inches thick.
lf they go,
it's sayonara in two microseconds.
All right. Enough of that bullshit.
Put her down on the roof
of the officers' quarters.
Sure.
Okay, Mir 2.
We've landed on the grand staircase.
You guys set to launch ?
Yeah. Launching Dunkin now.
Go, Charlie.
- Tether out.
Okay, Brock,
we're dropping down along the hull.
Roger that. Okay, drop down and go
into the first-class gangway door.
l want you guys working the ''D'' deck,
reception and the dining saloon.
Copy that.
- Tether out.
- Now left.
- l'm coming left.
(Brock) Snoop Dog is on the move.
We're headed down the stairwell.
Okay, Lewis. Drop down to ''B'' deck.
Okay. ''A'' deck.
(Lewis) Give me some rope, Captain.
''B'' deck. Get in there.
(Brock) Watch the doorframe.
l see it. l got it.
(banging)
(mechanical whirring)
(cracking)
We're good... Just chill, boss.
(Brock) Make your turn.
- (Lewis) Cable out, Captain.
- Make your turn.
Brock, we're at the piano.
You copy ?
(Brock) Okay, copy that.
(Brock) Right there, that's it !
- That's the bedroom door !
- l see it... l see it.
We're in !
We're in, baby, we're there !
(Brock) That's Hockley's bed.
That's where the son of a bitch slept.
(Lewis) Somebody left the water running.
Hold it. Go back to the right.
That wardrobe door... Get closer.
- You smelling something, boss ?
- l wanna see what's under it.
Gimme my hands, man.
(mechanical whirring)
All right... !
- Take it easy. lt might come apart.
- Okay.
Go ! Go, go, go !
Flip it over, flip it over. Go.
Keep going. Go, go, go.
Okay. Drop it.
Oh, baby, baby...
Are you seeing this, boss ?
lt's payday, boys.
(cheering)
Ka-ching !
We did it, Bobby !
(Lewis) Oh, yeah ! Who's the man !
Who's the best, baby ?
Say it, say it.
You are, Lewis.
(loud buzzing)
- Bobby, my cigar.
- Right here.
(cheering)
Okay, crack her open.
- Let me get around. Hang on.
- You getting it ?
Shit.
No diamond.
You know, boss,...
..the same thing happened to Geraldo,
and his career never recovered.
Turn the camera off.
Brock, the partners would
like to know how it's going.
Hey, Dave. Barry. Hi.
Look, it wasn't in the safe, but hey...
..don't worry about it.
There's plenty of places it could be.
The floor debris,
the mother's room...
- Purser's safe on ''C'' deck.
- Jimmy Hoffa's briefcase.
(Brock) A dozen other places.
You've got to trust my instincts.
l know we're close.
We just got to go through
a process of elimination.
Hang on a second.
Let me see that.
We might have something here, guys.
Where's the photo of the necklace ?
- We'll call you right back.
- Holy...
l'll be goddamned.
(TV)
Treasure hunter Brock Lovett
is best known for finding Spanish gold...
lt's okay. l'll feed you in a minute.
He's chartered a Russian sub to reach
the most famous wreck of all: Titanic.
He's with us live via satellite from
the Keldysh in the North Atlantic.
-Hello, Brock.
-Hello, Tracy.
Everyone knows
the stories of Titanic,...
..the nobility,
the band playing and all that.
l'm interested in the untold stories,
the secrets deep inside the hull.
We're using robot technology
to go further into the wreck...
..than anybody's ever done before.
You're at the centre of a controversy...
..over salvage rights, and ethics.
Many are calling you a grave robber.
Nobody called the recovery
of King Tut ''grave robbing''.
- What is it ?
- Turn that up, dear.
l have museum-trained experts here...
..making sure these relics
are treated properly.
Look at this drawing
we found just today.
A piece of paper that's been
underwater for 84 years...
..and my team were able
to preserve it intact.
Should this have remained unseen
at the bottom of the ocean for eternity ?
l'll be goddamned.
Brock !
There's a satellite call for you.
Bobby, we're launching.
You see these submersibles going in ?
Trust me, buddy.
You wanna take this call.
This better be good.
You gotta speak up.
She's kinda old.
Great.
This is Brock Lovett.
How can l help you, Mrs... ?
Calvert. Rose Calvert.
Mrs Calvert ?
l was just wondering if you'd found
the ''Heart of the Ocean'', Mr Lovett.
l said you wanted to take the call.
All right.
You have my attention, Rose.
Can you tell us who the woman
in the picture is ?
Oh, yes.
The woman in the picture is me.
She's a goddamned liar ! Some nutcase
seeking money or publicity !
God only knows why !
Like that Russian babe, Anaesthesia !
They're inbound !
Rose DeWitt Bukater died on Titanic
when she was 17.
Right.
lf she'd lived, she'd be over 100 by now.
101 next month.
So she's a very old goddamned liar !
l've done the background
on this woman...
..back to the '20s
when she was working as an actress.
An actress !
There's your first clue, Sherlock !
Her name was Rose Dawson back then.
She marries a guy named Calvert.
They move to Cedar Rapids and have kids.
Now Calvert's dead,
and Cedar Rapids, too.
Everybody who knows
about the diamond...
..is supposed to be dead
or on this boat, but she knows.
Doesn't exactly travel light,
does she ?
Mrs Calvert, l'm Brock Lovett.
Welcome to the Keldysh.
Let's get her inside.
Hi, Ms Calvert.
- Hi.
- Welcome to the Keldysh.
(Man) Hey.
Hey !
(knocking)
Yes ?
- Are your staterooms all right ?
- Very nice.
Have you met my granddaughter Lizzy ?
She takes care of me.
We metjust a few minutes ago.
Remember, Nana ? Up on deck ?
(Rose) There, that's nice.
Have to have my pictures when l travel.
ls there anything you'd like ?
Yes.
l would like to see my drawing.
(Brock) Louis XVl wore a fabulous stone,
the Blue Diamond of the Crown,...
..which disappeared in 1792.
About that time old Louis
lost everything, from the neck up.
The theory goes that
the Crown Diamond was chopped, too.
Recut into a heart shape that became
known as ''The Heart of the Ocean''.
Today it'd be worth more
than the Hope Diamond.
lt was a dreadful, heavy thing.
l only wore it this once.
You actually think this is you, Nana ?
lt is me, dear.
Wasn't l a dish ?
l tracked it down
through insurance records.
An old claim that was settled
under terms of absolute secrecy.
Can you tell me
who the claimant was, Rose ?
l imagine someone named Hockley.
Nathan Hockley, that's right.
Pittsburgh steel tycoon.
The claim was for a necklace his son
Caledon bought his fianc閑 - you -
..a week before he sailed on Titanic.
lt was filed right after the sinking,...
..so the diamond had to have
gone down with the ship.
You see the date ?
''April 14, 1912.''
lf your grandmother
is who she says she is,...
..she was wearing the diamond
the day the Titanic sank.
And that makes you my new best friend.
These are some of the things
we recovered from your stateroom.
This was mine !
How extraordinary !
And it looks the same as it did
the last time l saw it.
The reflection has changed a bit.
Are you ready to go back to Titanic ?
Okay, here we go. She hits the berg
on the starboard side, right ?
She bumps along, punching holes
along the side, below the waterline.
Then the forward compartments
start to flood.
As the water rises, it spills over
the watertight bulkheads...
..which don't go any higher
than ''E'' deck.
So now as the bow goes down,
the stern rises up,...
..slow at first,
then faster and faster,...
..until she's got her whole ass
up in the air. A big ass.
We're talking 20,000, 30,000 tons, okay ?
The hull's not designed to deal
with that pressure, so what happens ?
She splits, right down to the keel,
and the stern falls back level.
As the bow sinks
it pulls the stern vertical...
..and then finally detaches.
The stern section bobs there
like a cork for a few minutes,...
..floods, and finally goes under
about 2.20am.
Two hours and 40 minutes
after the collision.
The bow section planes away,
landing about half a mile away,...
..going 20, 30 knots
when it hits the ocean floor.
Pretty cool, huh ?
Thank you for that fine
forensic analysis, Mr Bodine.
Of course, the experience of it was...
somewhat different.
Will you share it with us ?
- l'm taking her to rest.
- No.
- Come on, Nana.
- No !
Tape recorder.
Tell us, Rose.
lt's been 84 years.
Try to remember anything.
Anything at all.
Do you want to hear this or not,
Mr Lovett ?
lt's been 84 years...
..and l can still smell the fresh paint.
The china had never been used.
The sheets had never been slept in.
Titanic was called
''The Ship of Dreams''.
And it was.
lt really was.
All third-class passengers...
..with a forward berth,...
..this way, please.
This queue. Right here.
Big boat, uh ?
- Daddy, it's a ship.
- You're right.
(car horn)
Why all the fuss ? lt doesn't look
any bigger than the Mauretania.
You can be blas?about some things,
Rose, but not about Titanic.
lt's 100 feet longer...
..and far more luxurious.
Your daughter is difficult
to impress, Ruth.
So this is the ship
they say is unsinkable.
God himself could not sink this ship.
Sir, you have to check your baggage
through the main terminal.
l put my faith in you, good sir.
Now kindly see my man.
Yes, sir. My pleasure, sir.
Right.
All the trunks from that car there,...
..12 from here, and the safe,...
..to the Parlour Suite, rooms B52, 54, 56.
(whistle)
Ladies...
Better hurry.
- My coat ?
- l have it, miss.
All third-class passengers
queue here for health inspection.
Chin up.
Welcome aboard, ma'am.
Welcome to Titanic.
(Rose)
lt was the ship of dreams
-to everyone else.
To me it was a slave ship...
..taking me back to America in chains.
Outwardly l was everything
a well-brought-up girl should be.
lnside, l was screaming.
(steam whistle)
(speaking Swedish)
Jack, you are pazzo.
You bet everything we have.
When you got nothing,
you got nothing to lose.
(Swedish) You moron.
l can't believe you bet our tickets.
Sven ?
All right... moment of truth.
Somebody's life's about to change.
Fabrizio ?
Niente.
Olaf ?
Nothing.
Sven ?
Uh-oh. Two pair.
l'm sorry, Fabrizio.
''Sorry'' ? You bet all the money !
l'm sorry. You're not gonna see
your mom for a long time.
Cos we're going to America !
Full house, boys !
Whoa !
Yeah !
Dio mio, grazie !
(cursing in Swedish)
Come on !
Figlio di puttana !
l'm going home !
(cursing in Swedish)
l go to America !
No, mate.
Titanic go to America, in five minutes.
Come on ! Come on, here !
Andiamo !
We're riding in high style now !
We're a couple of swells !
Practically goddamn royalty,
ragazzo mio !
You see, it's my destino !
l go to America to be millionario !
(Driver) Whoa ! Whoa !
Bastardo !
- You're pazzo !
- Maybe, but l've got the tickets !
Come on, l thought you were fast !
- Aspetta !
- Wait ! Hey, wait !
We're passengers ! Passengers !
- Have you been through the inspection ?
- Of course !
Anyway, we don't have lice.
We're Americans.
Right. Come aboard.
We're the luckiest sons of bitches
in the world !
(ship's horn)
Goodbye !
- You know somebody ?
- That's not the point.
- Goodbye ! l'll miss you !
- Goodbye ! l will never forget you !
(crowd cheering)
Go left, darling.
G60, G60...
Excuse me, ma'am.
Oh, right here.
Hey, how you doing ?
Jack. Nice to meet you.
l'm Jack Dawson. Nice to meet you.
How you doing ?
Who says you get top bunk, huh ?
(Swedish) Where's Sven ?
This is your private deck, sir.
Would you be requiring anything ?
- Mm-mm.
- Excuse me.
- This one ?
- No... lt had a lot of faces on it.
This is the one.
Would you like all of them out, miss ?
Yes... We need a little colour
in this room.
Put it in there, in the wardrobe.
God, not those finger paintings again !
Waste of money !
The difference between Cal's taste
and mine...
..is that l have some.
They're fascinating.
Like being inside a dream
or something.
There's truth, but no logic.
- What's the artist's name ?
- Something Picasso.
''Something Picasso''.
He won't amount to a thing. Trust me.
- Put the Degas in the bedroom.
- At least they were cheap.
Put it in the wardrobe.
(Rose)
At Cherbourg, a woman
came aboard named Margaret Brown.
We all called her Molly.
History would call her
''The Unsinkable Molly Brown''.
l wasn't about to wait all day, sonny.
Here, think you can manage ?
Her husband had struck gold
someplace out west...
..and she was what Mother called
''new money''.
By next afternoon we were steaming
west from the coast of lreland...
..with nothing out ahead of us but ocean.
Take her to sea, Mr Murdoch.
- Let's stretch her legs.
- Yes, sir.
- All ahead full, Mr Moody.
- Very good, sir.
(bells ringing)
All ahead full.
(Man) All ahead full !
Come on, lads. Step lively.
Let's stoke them right up !
We're going full ahead !
21 knots, sir.
Hey, look, look, look !
Look, look !
See it ?
There's another one ! See him ?
Look at that one !
Look at him jump !
Whoo-hoo !
Whoo !
l can see the Statue of Liberty
already !
Very small, of course.
l'm the king of the world !
(whooping and yelling)
She is the largest moving object
ever made by the hand of man...
..in all history.
Our master shipbuilder,
Mr Andrews,...
..designed her.
l knocked her together...
..but the idea was Mr lsmay's.
He envisioned a steamer
so grand in scale...
..that its supremacy
would never be challenged.
And here she is...
..willed into solid reality.
Hear, hear.
Salmon.
You know l don't like that, Rose.
She knows.
We'll both have the lamb, rare,
with very little mint sauce.
You like lamb, right, sweet pea ?
Are you gonna cut her meat
for her, too, Cal ?
Hey, who thought of the name
''Titanic'' ? Was it you, Bruce ?
Yes, actually.
l wanted to convey sheer size,
and the size means stability,...
..luxury, and, above all, strength.
Do you know of Dr Freud, Mr lsmay ?
His ideas about male preoccupation
with size might interest you.
- What's gotten into you ?
- Excuse me.
l do apologise.
She's a pistol, Cal.
Hope you can handle her.
Well, l may have to start minding
what she reads, Mrs Brown.
Freud... who is he ?
ls he a passenger ?
..turns the propeller,...
..makes these waves,...
..makes them spin.
(Fabrizio) The ship is nice, uh ?
- Yeah, it's an lrish ship.
- ls English, no ?
No, it was built in lreland.
15,000 lrishmen built this ship.
That's typical.
First-class dogs come down here
to take a shite.
lt lets us know where we rank.
Like we could forget ?
l'm Tommy Ryan.
- Jack Dawson.
- Fabrizio.
Hi. Do you make any money
with your drawings ?
Oh, forget it, boyo. You'd as like
have angels fly out of your arse...
..as get next to the likes of her.
(Rose)
l saw my whole life
as if l'd already lived it,...
..an endless parade of parties
and cotillions,...
..yachts and polo matches.
Always the same narrow people,
the same mindless chatter.
l felt like l was standing
at a great precipice...
..with no-one to pull me back.
No-one who cared, or even noticed.
(Rose sobbing)
(Rose running and sobbing)
Don't do it.
Stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Come on.
- Gimme your hand. l'll pull you back.
- No !
Stay where you are. l mean it.
l'll let go.
No, you won't.
What do you mean, no, l won't ?
Don't presume to tell me
what l will and will not do.
Well, you would've done it already.
You're distracting me. Go away.
l can't.
l'm involved now.
You let go and l'm gonna
have to jump in there after you.
Don't be absurd. You'll be killed.
- l'm a good swimmer.
- The fall alone would kill you.
lt would hurt.
l'm not saying it wouldn't.
But l'm more concerned
about that water being so cold.
How cold ?
Freezing.
Maybe a couple of degrees over.
You ever, uh...
..ever been to Wisconsin ?
What ?
They have some of the coldest winters.
l grew up there, near Chippewa Falls.
When l was a kid,
me and my father went ice fishing...
..out on Lake Wissota.
lce fishing is where you...
l know what ice fishing is !
Sorry.
You just seem like, you know,
kind of an indoor girl.
Anyway, l, uh...
l fell through some thin ice.
And l'm telling you...
..water that cold,
like right down there,...
..it hits you like a thousand knives
stabbing you all over.
You can't breathe...
You can't think...
At least not about anything
but the pain.
Which is why l'm not looking forward
to jumping in there after you.
Like l said,...
..l don't have a choice.
l'm hoping you'll come back
over the rail and get me off the hook here.
You're crazy.
That's what everybody says, but...
With all due respect, miss, l'm not the one
hanging off the back of a ship.
Come on.
Come on, gimme your hand.
You don't wanna do this.
Whew !
l'm Jack Dawson.
Rose DeWitt Bukater.
l'll have to get you
to write that down !
Come on.
(screams)
l got you ! Come on !
Come on !
(screams)
Help ! Please !
- Please help me !
- Listen ! Listen to me !
l've got you. l won't let go.
Now pull yourself up. Come on !
Come on.
That's right.
You can do it.
l got you.
What's all this ?
You stand back !
And don't move an inch !
Fetch the master-at-arms !
Care for a brandy ?
(Cal) This is completely unacceptable !
How dare you put your hands
on my fianc閑 !
- Look at me, you filth !
- Cal...
- What do you think you were doing ?
- Cal, stop ! lt was an accident.
An accident ?
lt was.
Stupid, really.
l was leaning over and l slipped.
l was leaning far over to see the, uh...
..uh...
..the, uh...
- Propellers ?
- Propellers. And l slipped.
l would have gone overboard,
but Mr Dawson here saved me...
..and almost went over himself.
- She wanted to see the propellers !
- Women and machinery do not mix.
Was that the way of it ?
Yeah. Yeah, that was pretty much it.
The boy's a hero, then.
Good for you, son. Well done.
So it's all's well, and, uh...
..back to our brandy, eh ?
Look at you. You must be freezing.
Let's get you inside.
Perhaps a little something for the boy ?
Of course.
Mr Lovejoy, l think a 20 should do it.
ls that the going rate
for saving the woman you love ?
Rose is displeased. What to do...
l know.
Perhaps you could join us
for dinner tomorrow evening...
..to regale our group with...
your heroic tale.
Sure. Count me in.
Good. Settled, then.
- This should be interesting.
- Mmm.
(whistles)
Can l, uh... bum a smoke ?
You'll want to tie those.
lt's interesting.
The young lady slips so suddenly...
..and you still had time to remove
your jacket and your shoes.
(music box)
(knock at door)
l know you've been melancholy.
l don't pretend to know why.
l intended to save this...
..until the engagement gala...
..next week.
But... l thought...
..tonight.
Good gracious !
A reminder of my feelings for you.
ls it a... ?
Diamond ? Yes.
56 carats to be exact.
lt was worn by Louis XVl,
and they called it ''Le Coeur de la Mer''.
(Both) The Heart of the Ocean.
lt's overwhelming.
Well, it's for royalty.
We are royalty, Rose.
You know, there's nothing
l couldn't give you.
There's nothing l'd deny you...
..if you would not deny me.
Oh, open your heart to me, Rose.
(Jack) Well, l've been on my own
since l was 15, since my folks died.
l had no close kin
in that part of the country.
So l left and l haven't been back since.
You could just call me a tumbleweed
blowing in the wind.
Well, Rose, we've walked about a mile
around this boat deck...
..and chewed over how great
the weather's been and how l grew up,...
..but l reckon that's not
why you came to talk to me, is it ?
- Mr Dawson, l...
- Jack.
Jack.
l want to thank you for what you did.
Notjust for... for pulling me back,
but for your discretion.
You're welcome.
Look, l know what
you must be thinking.
Poor little rich girl.
What does she know about misery ?
No... No, that's not what l was thinking.
l was thinking
what could have happened to this girl...
..to make her think she had no way out.
Well, l...
lt was everything.
lt was my whole world...
..and all the people in it.
The inertia of my life... plunging
ahead, and me powerless to stop it.
God ! Look at that thing !
You would've gone
straight to the bottom.
500 invitations have gone out.
All of Philadelphia society
will be there,...
..and all the while l feel
l'm standing in a crowded room...
..screaming at the top of my lungs,
and no-one even looks up.
Do you love him ?
Pardon me ?
You shouldn't be asking me this.
lt's a simple question.
Do you love the guy or not ?
- This is not a suitable conversation.
- Can't you just answer the question ?
This is absurd. You don't know me
and l don't know you,...
..and we are not having this conversation.
You are rude and uncouth
and... l am leaving now.
Jack... Mr Dawson,
it's been a pleasure.
l sought you out to thank you...
- And you insulted me.
- You deserved it.
- Right.
- l thought you were leaving.
- l am.
You are so annoying !
Wait.
l don't have to leave.
This is my part of the ship.
You leave.
Well, well, well !
Now who's being rude ?
What is this stupid thing
you're carrying around ?
So what are you ?
An artist or something ?
Well... these are rather good.
They're, uh...
they're very good, actually.
Jack, this is exquisite work.
- They didn't like them in old Paris.
- Paris ?!
You do get around, for a poor...
Well, uh, uh,
a person of limited means.
A poor guy. You can say it.
Well, well, well !
And these were drawn from life ?
That's the good thing about Paris.
Lots of girls
willing to take their clothes off.
You liked this woman.
You used her several times.
Well, she had beautiful hands,
you see ?
l think you must have had
a love affair with her.
No, no, no.
Just with her hands.
She was a one-legged prostitute.
See ?
Oh !
She had a good sense of humour,
though.
And this lady...
She used to sit at this bar
every night...
..wearing all her jewellery,
waiting for her long-lost love.
Called her Madame Bijoux.
See how her clothes
are all moth-eaten ?
Well, you have a gift, Jack.
You do.
You see people.
l see you.
And ?
You wouldn't have jumped.
But the purpose of university
is to find a suitable husband.
Rose has already done that.
Here comes that vulgar Brown woman.
Quickly, get up before she sits with us.
Hello, girls.
- l was hoping l'd catch you at tea.
- We're awfully sorry you missed it.
The Countess and l
were just off to the boat deck.
What a lovely idea.
l need to catch up on my gossip.
Countess.
So you've not yet lit
the last four boilers ?
l don't see the need.
We are making excellent time.
The press knows the size of Titanic.
Now l want them to marvel at her speed.
We must give them
something new to print.
This maiden voyage of Titanic...
..must make headlines.
Mr lsmay, l would prefer
not to push the engines...
..until they've been properly run in.
Of course, l'm just a passenger.
l leave it to you to decide what's best.
But a glorious end to your final trip
if we arrive on Tuesday night...
..and surprise them all.
Make the morning papers.
Retire with a bang, eh, EJ ?
Good man.
Well, after that l worked
on a squid boat in Monterey.
Then l went to the pier
in Santa Monica...
..and started doing portraits there
for 10 cents apiece.
Why can't l be like you, Jack ?
Just head out for the horizon...
..whenever l feel like it.
Say we'll go there sometime to that pier...
..even if we only just talk about it.
No, we'll do it.
We'll drink cheap beer.
Ride on the roller coaster.
Then we'll ride horses on the beach...
..right in the surf. But like a real cowboy.
Not that sidesaddle stuff.
You mean, one leg on each side ?
Yeah.
- Can you show me ?
- Sure. lf you like.
- Teach me to ride like a man.
- And chew tobacco like a man.
And spit like a man !
They didn't teach you that ?
No !
Come on, l'll show you.
l'll show you how. Come on.
Jack ! No ! Jack ! No !
Wait, Jack. No, Jack.
- l couldn't possibly, Jack.
- Watch closely.
- That's disgusting !
- Your turn.
Pitiful !
You really gotta hawk it back.
Use your arms. Arc your neck.
See the range on that thing ?
(Jack) Okay, go.
You gotta work on it. Really try
and hawk it up and get some body to it.
(snorting)
Mother.
May l introduce Jack Dawson ?
Charmed, l'm sure.
(Rose)
The others were gracious
about the man who saved my life...
..but my mother looked at him
like an insect,...
..a dangerous insect,...
..which must be squashed quickly.
Sounds like you're a good man
to have around in a sticky spot.
(trumpet playing fanfare)
Why do they always announce dinner
like a damn cavalry charge ?
Shall we go dress, Mother ?
See you at dinner, Jack.
Uh, son ?
Son !
Do you have any idea what you're doing ?
Not really.
Well, you're about
to go into the snakepit.
What are you planning to wear ?
l figured.
Come on.
l was right ! You and my son
are just about the same size.
Pretty close.
(whistles)
You shine up like a new penny !
Good evening, sir.
(orchestra playing
''On the Beautiful Blue Danube'')
Good evening.
Hello.
(Cal) There are several thousand tons
of Hockley steel...
..in this very ship.
Then we'll know who to hold
accountable if there's a problem.
There is the Countess.
- Hello, my dear.
- Good evening, Cal.
(Cal) So good to see you.
l saw that in a nickelodeon once
and l always wanted to do it.
(Ruth) l'll see you at dinner.
Darling ?
Surely you remember Mr Dawson ?
Dawson ?
Well, it's amazing !
You could almost pass for a gentleman !
Almost.
Extraordinary !
(Ruth) My dear, it's delightful to see you.
What a remarkable voyage this is !
Mad, isn't it ?
There's the Countess of Rothes.
And, um... that's John Jacob Astor,
the richest man on the ship.
His little wifey, Madeleine,
is my age and in a delicate condition.
See how she's trying to hide it ?
- Quite the scandal.
- Hmm !
And that's Benjamin Guggenheim
and his mistress Madame Aubert.
Mrs Guggenheim is at home
with the children.
And over here we have Sir Cosmo
and Lucille Lady Duff-Gordon.
She designs naughty lingerie.
Very popular with the royals.
Congratulations, Hockley.
She's splendid.
Why, thank you.
Care to escort a lady to dinner ?
Certainly.
Sweet pea ?
(Cal) Sweet pea !
Ain't nothin' to it, Jack.
They love money,...
..so just pretend like you own
a goldmine and you're in the club.
Hey, Astor !
Well, hello, Molly !
Nice to see you.
JJ, Madeleine,
l'd like you to meet Jack Dawson.
- How do you do ?
- Pleasure.
Hello, Jack.
Are you of the Boston Dawsons ?
No... the Chippewa Falls Dawsons,
actually.
Oh, yes...
(Rose)
He must have been nervous,
but he never faltered.
They assumed he was one of them.
Heir to a railroad fortune, perhaps.
New money, obviously,
but still a member of the club.
Mother, of course,
could always be counted upon.
Tell us of the accommodations
in steerage, Mr Dawson.
l hear they're quite good.
The best l've seen, ma'am.
Hardly any rats.
(laughter)
Mr Dawson is joining us
from the third class.
He was of some assistance
to my fianc閑 last night.
Mr Dawson is quite a fine artist.
He was kind enough to show me
some of his work today.
Rose and l differ somewhat
in our definition of fine art.
Not to impugn your work, sir.
(clears throat)
(lsmay) She may be mine on paper...
..but in the eyes of God
she belongs to Thomas Andrews.
Are these all for me ?
Start from the outside
and work your way in.
- He knows every rivet in her.
- Your ship is a wonder, Mr Andrews.
Thank you, Rose.
- How do you take your caviar, sir ?
- No caviar for me, thanks.
Never did like it much.
And where exactly do you live,
Mr Dawson ?
Well, right now my address
is the RMS Titanic.
After that l'm on God's good humour.
And how is it you have means to travel ?
l work my way from place to place.
You know, tramp steamers and such.
But l won my ticket on Titanic here
at a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
All life is a game of luck.
A real man makes his own luck, Archie.
Right, Dawson ?
Mm.
And you find that sort of rootless
existence appealing, do you ?
Well, yes, ma'am, l do.
l mean... Got everything l need
right here with me.
Got air in my lungs
and a few sheets of paper.
l love waking up in the morning
not knowing what's gonna happen...
..or who l'm gonna meet,
where l'm gonna wind up.
The other night l slept under a bridge.
Now l'm on the grandest ship
in the world...
..having champagne
with you fine people.
l figure life's a gift
and l don't intend on wasting it.
You never know what hand
you're gonna get dealt next.
You learn to take life
as it comes at you,...
..to make each day count.
Well said, Jack.
Hear, hear !
To making it count.
(All) To making it count.
Bravo !
(Molly laughing)
Mr Brown had no idea
l'd hidden the money in the stove !
So he comes home drunk as a pig
and he lights a fire !
Next it'll be brandies
in the smoking room.
Join me in a brandy, gentlemen ?
Now they retreat
into a cloud of smoke...
..and congratulate each other
on being masters of the universe.
Ladies, thank you for your company.
- May l escort you to the cabin ?
- No, l'll stay here.
Here you go, Molly.
(Archie) Joining us, Dawson ?
Don't want to stay with the women,
do you ?
No, thanks.
l've gotta be heading back.
Probably best. lt'll be all business
and politics. Wouldn't interest you.
But, Dawson... Good of you to come.
Jack, must you go ?
Time for me to row
with the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
(clock chiming)
So you wanna go to a real party ?
ls okay l put my hand here ?
Okay !
Talla frikken svenska ?
What ?
(repeats phrase)
l can't understand you.
(glass shatters)
Hey... !
Bravo ! Bravo !
Come on, guys, let's go ! Ho !
l'm gonna dance with her now,
all right ?
Come on.
Come on !
Come with me.
Jack... Jack, wait !
l can't do this.
We have to get a bit closer.
Like this.
You're still my best girl, Cora.
- l don't know the steps.
- Neither do l. Just go with it.
Don't think.
Wait, Jack ! Wait ! Stop, Jack !
Wait !
(Jack) Yeah !
Jack... No !
Whaaa...
..jurisdiction of the Sherman Act,
so my lawyers will argue.
That's what Rockefeller said,
but the court is not swallowing it.
What ?
You think a first-class girl can't drink ?
Get outta here !
You all right ?
Two out of three, two out of three.
So...
You think you're big, tough men ?
Let's see you do this.
Hold this for me, Jack.
Hold it up.
Ow !
Jesus, Mary and Joseph !
- You all right ?
- l haven't done that in years !
Go see Maggie, lads. Let's go !
Coffee, sir ?
l had hoped you would
come to me last night.
l was tired.
Your exertions below decks
were no doubt exhausting.
l see you had that undertaker
of a manservant follow me. How typical.
You will never behave like that again,
Rose. Do you understand ?
l'm not a foreman in one of your mills
that you can command.
l'm your fianc閑.
My fianc閑 ? My fianc閑 ?!
Yes, you are, and my wife !
M wife in practice if not yet by law,
so you will honour me.
You will honour me
the way a wife is required to.
l will not be made a fool of.
ls this in any way unclear ?
No.
Good.
Excuse me.
Miss Rose !
- We had a little... accident.
- That's all right, Miss Rose.
l'm sorry, Trudy. Let me help you.
lt's all right, miss.
Tea, Trudy.
Yes, ma'am.
You're not to see that boy again.
Do you understand me ?
Rose, l forbid it.
Oh, stop it, Mother.
You'll give yourself a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious.
You know the money's gone.
Of course l know it's gone.
You remind me every day.
Your father left us nothing
but a legacy of bad debts...
..hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card
we have to play.
l don't understand you.
lt is a fine match with Hockley.
lt will ensure our survival.
How can you put this on my shoulders ?
Why are you being so selfish ?
l'm being selfish ?
Do you want to see me
working as a seamstress ?
ls that what you want ?
To see our fine things
sold at auction ?
Our memories scattered to the winds !
lt's so unfair.
Of course it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
Hmm ?
# Protect them by thy guardian hand...
# ..from every peril on the land.
# O spirit, whom the father sent...
# ..to spread across the firmament.
# O wind of heaven, by thy might...
# ..save all who dare the eagle's flight.
#And keep them by thy watchful...
Hello, Mr Andrews.
Hello, Jack.
- Sir...
- l just need to talk to somebody...
You're not supposed to be in here.
# ..fire and foe,...
# ..protect them...
- You don't remember me ?
- No, l don't.
- You'll have to turn around.
- He'll tell you.
l just...
Mr Hockley and Mrs DeWitt Bukater...
..continue to be appreciative
of your assistance.
They asked me to give you this
in gratitude.
l don't want your money...
You hold a third-class ticket. Your
presence here is no longer appropriate.
Please, l just wanna speak to Rose...
Gentlemen, please see that Mr Dawson
gets back to where he belongs...
..and that he stays there.
Yes, sir.
Come along, you.
# O hear us when we cry to Thee...
# ..for those in peril on the sea.
- Why two steering wheels ?
- We only use this near shore.
Sir, another ice warning.
This one's from the Noordam.
Thank you, Sparks.
Oh, not to worry.
Quite normal for this time of year.
ln fact, we're speeding up.
l've just ordered the last boilers lit.
Okay, son, wind it up tight
like l showed you.
Okay, let it go.
- Was good, wasn't it ?
- Quite nice.
That's excellent, son.
(Rose) Mr Andrews, forgive me...
l did the sum in my head...
With the number of lifeboats
times the capacity you mentioned...
..it seems there are not enough
for everyone.
About half, actually.
Rose, you miss nothing, do you ?
ln fact,
l put in these new type davits...
..which can take an extra row of boats.
But it was thought by some
that the deck would look too cluttered...
..so l was overruled.
Waste of deck space
on an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly, young Rose.
l have built you a good ship,
strong and true.
She is all the lifeboat you need.
Just keep heading aft.
Come on.
Jack, this is impossible.
l can't see you.
- l need to talk to you.
- No, Jack, no.
Jack, l'm engaged.
l'm marrying Cal.
l love Cal.
Rose... you're no picnic.
You're a spoiled little brat, even.
But you're the most amazingly
astounding, wonderful girl,...
..woman,...
- ..that l've ever known, and...
- Jack...
Let me try and get this out.
You're ama...
l'm not an idiot.
l know how the world works.
l've got ten bucks in my pocket
and l have nothing to offer you.
l understand.
But l'm too involved now.
You jump, l jump, remember ?
l can't turn away without knowing
you'll be all right. That's all l want.
Well, l'm fine.
l'll be fine... Really.
Really ?
l don't think so.
They've got you trapped, Rose,
and you'll die if you don't break free.
Maybe not right away
because you're strong, but...
..that fire that l love about you, Rose,...
..that fire is gonna burn out.
lt's not up to you to save me, Jack.
You're right.
Only you can do that.
l'm going back.
Leave me alone.
Tell Lucille about the disaster
you had with the stationer's.
The invitations
had to be sent back twice.
Oh, my dear !
And the dreadful bridesmaids' gowns
- what an odyssey that has been !
Rose decided she wanted lavender.
She knows l detest the colour,
so she did it to spite me.
lf only you'd come to me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs
in ''La Mode lllustr閑''.
They were for the Duchess
of Marlborough's youngest.
They were quite charming.
But l think you'll agree, my dear,...
..together we've created something
of a phoenix from the ashes !
Hello, Jack.
l changed my mind.
- They said you might be...
- Shh...
Give me your hand.
Now close your eyes.
Go on.
Step up.
Now hold on to the railing.
- Keep your eyes closed. Don't peek.
- l'm not.
Step up onto the rail.
Hold on... Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
Do you trust me ?
l trust you.
All right...
Open your eyes.
l'm flying !
Jack !
# Come, Josephine,
on my flying machine,...
# ..going up, she goes,
up, she goes...
That was the last time
Titanic ever saw daylight.
So we're up to dusk
the night of the sinking.
Six hours to go.
Smith's standing there, the iceberg
warning in his fucking hand,...
..and he's ordering more speed.
26 years of experience
working against him.
He figures anything big enough
to sink the ship they'll see in time to turn.
But the ship's too big with too small
a rudder. Doesn't corner worth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
lt's quite proper, l assure you !
This is the sitting room.
- Will this light do ?
- What ?
Don't artists need good light ?
(French accent) l am not
used to working in such...
..horrible conditions.
Monet !
- Do you know his work ?
- Of course !
Look at his use of colour here !
l know, it's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting
this hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him
any time soon ?
Not as long as the cigars
and brandy hold out.
That's nice !
What is it ? A sapphire ?
A diamond.
A very rare diamond.
Jack, l want you to draw me
like one of your French girls...
..wearing this.
All right.
Wearing only this.
The last thing l need...
..is another picture of me
looking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer...
..l expect to get what l want.
Over on the bed... the couch.
Go... lie down.
Tell me when it looks right.
Put your arm back the way it was.
Right.
Put that other arm up...
That hand right by your face.
Right.
Now, head down...
Eyes to me. Keep them on me.
And try to stay still.
So serious !
l believe you are blushing,
Mr Big Artiste.
l can't imagine
Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
- Just relax your face.
- Sorry.
No laughing.
My heart was pounding
the whole time.
lt was the most erotic moment
of my life.
Up until then, at least.
So what happened next ?
You mean... did we do it ?
Sorry to disappoint you, Mr Bodine.
Jack was very professional.
Thank you.
What are you doing ?
Will you put this back
in the safe for me ?
Would you excuse me ?
None of the stewards have seen her.
This is absurd.
lt's a ship. There's only
so many places she could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
- Clear.
- Yes.
l don't think l've ever seen
such a flat calm.
Like a millpond.
Not a breath of wind.
lt will make the bergs harder to see...
..with no breaking water at the base.
Well, l'm off.
Maintain speed and heading,
Mr Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
lt's getting cold.
You look nice.
(Lovejoy) Miss Rose ?
My drawings !
(door closes)
Wait !
Wait, wait, wait !
Go, go !
Down, down !
Bye !
Sorry !
Pretty tough for a valet, this fellow.
- Seems more like a cop.
- l think he was.
(Jack) Oh, shit !
No, over here !
Quick !
(boiler blasting)
Now what !
What !
What are you two doing here ?
You shouldn't be here !
lt's dangerous !
(Jack) Carry on !
Don't mind us ! You're doing a greatjob !
Keep up the good work !
Look what we have here, huh ?
(Rose clears throat)
Thank you.
(honks horn)
Where to, miss ?
To the stars.
Are you nervous ?
No.
Put your hands on me, Jack.
(Crewman) God, it's bloody cold.
You know, l can smell ice,
you know... when it's near.
Bollocks.
But l can, all right ?
Did you ever find those binoculars ?
Haven't seen them since Southampton.
Well, l'll be on my rounds. Cheerio.
You're trembling.
Don't worry. l'll be all right.
They ran down there.
Right.
Anything missing ?
l've got a better idea.
Gotcha !
(Rose laughing)
Did you see those guys' faces ?
Did you see the... ?
When the ship docks...
..l'm getting off with you.
This is crazy.
l know ! lt doesn't make any sense.
That's why l trust it.
Oh, yes... Here, look at this.
- Look at that, would ya ?
- They're a bit warmer than we are.
Well, if that's what it takes for us
to get warm, l'd rather not !
Bugger me !
(alarm bell clanging)
(phone)
Pick up, you bastards !
(phone ringing)
- ls there anyone there ?!
- Yes, what do you see ?
lceberg ! Right ahead !
Thank you.
Hard to starboard !
(ringing)
(Crewman) Turn ! Turn ! Steady !
(bell clangs)
Full astern !
Hard over !
Helm's hard over, sir !
(ringing)
Go, lads ! Go !
Shut all the dampers !
Shut them !
(dampers slamming)
Hold it !
Now ! Engage the reversing engine !
(engine stops)
(engine restarts)
Why aren't they turning ?!
ls it hard over ?!
lt is, yes, sir, hard over !
Come on... come on... come on...
Turn...
Yes...
lt's going to hit !
Jesus Christ !
(glass tinkling)
Jesus...
Hard to port !
(Crewman) Hard to port !
(men screaming)
Get back !
Come on, let's go !
They're closing the doors !
Get out !
Get out ! Get out !
Get out the door !
Go on !
Come on, lads !
Go, lads, go !
Get out !
Oh, my God...
That was a close shave, weren't it ?
Smell ice, can ya ? Bleedin' Christ !
Note the time and enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr Murdoch ?
An iceberg, sir.
l put her hard to starboard
and ran the engines full astern...
..but it was too close.
l tried to port round it, but she hit and...
- Close the watertight doors.
- Doors are closed, sir.
All stop.
(ringing)
Find the carpenter.
Get him to sound the ship.
Yes, sir !
(Fabrizio) Porca puttana !
Che cazzo e ?
Come on,
let's get the hell out of here !
Come on, hurry up !
Why have the engines stopped ?
l felt a shudder.
l shouldn't worry, madam.
We've likely thrown a propeller blade.
- May l bring you anything ?
- No, thank you.
- Did you see anything ?
- l don't see anything now, do you ?
lf this is the direction the rats are going,
that's good enough for me.
Please, sir, please...
everything's under control.
- You there.
- Sir, there is no emergency.
- l have been robbed.
- Get the master-at-arms.
- Now, you moron !
- Yes, sir.
(men laughing)
Hey, you're gonna miss the fun.
- Did you see what happened ?
- No. Apparently, it hit over there.
lt's flooded eight feet
and the mail hold is worse.
- Can you shore up ?
- Not unless the pumps get ahead.
- Have you seen the mail-hold damage ?
- No, she's already underwater.
This is bad.
We should tell Mother and Cal.
l think they're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything.
l want the entire room photographed.
(Rose) Just keep holding my hand.
We've been looking for you, miss.
(Rose) Well, here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
lndeed. Two things dear to me
have disappeared this evening.
Now that one is back, l've an idea
where to find the other. Search him.
- Take your coat off, sir.
- Now what ?
Cal, we're in the middle
of an emergency.
What's going on ?
- ls this it ?
- That's it.
This is horseshit !
Don't you believe it, Rose !
- He couldn't have.
- Of course he could.
But l was with him the whole time.
Perhaps he did it while you were
putting your clothes back on, dear.
Rose, they put it in my pocket.
Shut up.
lt isn't even your pocket.
Property of AL Ryerson.
- That was reported stolen.
- l borrowed it. l was gonna return it.
- We have an honest thief, do we ?
- You know l didn't do this, Rose.
Don't you believe them, Rose.
You know l didn't do it.
You know l didn't do it, Rose !
Come on, son. There's a good lad.
Come on.
You know l didn't do it !
You know me !
(lsmay) Most unfortunate, Captain.
Water... 14 feet above the keel
in 10 minutes...
..in the forepeak, in all three holds
and in boiler room six.
That's right, sir.
- When can we get under way, damn it !
- That's five compartments !
She can stay afloat with the first four
compartments breached, but not five.
Not five.
As she goes down by the head...
..the water will spill over
the bulkheads, from one to the next.
Back and back.
There's no stopping it.
The pumps...
The pumps buy you time,
but minutes only.
From this moment,
no matter what we do,...
..Titanic will founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron, sir.
l assure you she can,...
..and she will.
lt is a mathematical certainty.
How much time ?
An hour...
Two at most.
And how many aboard, Mr Murdoch ?
2,200 souls on board, sir.
Well, l believe you may get
your headlines, Mr lsmay.
Oh, it is a little slut, isn't it ?
Look at me when l'm talking to you !
(knock at door)
- Mr Hockley ?
- Not now ! We're busy !
Sir, please put on your lifebelt...
l said not now.
l'm sorry but it's Captain's orders.
Now, please, dress warmly.
lt's quite cold out tonight.
May l suggest topcoats and hats ?
This is ridiculous.
Not to worry, miss.
l am sure it's just a precaution.
Everybody up ! Lifebelts on !
What's he on about ?
- Lifebelts on !
- What's the ruckus ?
Just put your lifebelts on !
(Crewman) CQD ?
Sir ?
That's right. CQD. The distress call.
That's our position.
Tell whoever responds
that we're going down by the head...
..and need immediate assistance.
Blimey !
Keep lowering ! Keep lowering !
Mr Wilde !
Where are the passengers ?
We moved them back inside.
lt's too damn cold and noisy for them.
(blows whistle)
Help with these lines !
(orchestra playing
''Alexander's Ragtime Band'')
Care for a drink, sir ?
Hey, sonny, what's doing ?
You got us all trussed up here...
- ..and now we're cooling our heels.
- Sorry, ma'am. Let me find out.
l don't think anybody knows
what the hell's going on.
lt's the goddamned English
doing everything by the... book.
There's no need for language, Mr Hockley.
Go and turn the heaters on in our rooms.
l'd like a cup of tea when l return.
Yes, ma'am.
(Man) This ship
has 15 watertight barricades.
(Crewman) Would you
put your lifebelt on, please ?
Mr Andrews...
l saw the iceberg,
and l see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
You're certain ?
Yes. ln an hour or so...
..all this will be
at the bottom of the Atlantic.
What ?
Tell only who you must. l don't want
to be responsible for a panic.
And get to a boat quickly. Don't wait.
You remember what l told you
about the boats ?
Yes...
l understand.
Over here, sir.
Sir, they need you in the second-class
purser's office. There's a mob up there.
- Go on. l'll keep an eye on him.
- Aye. Right.
Sir ! Carpathia says
they're making 17 knots.
Full steam for them, sir.
- She's the only one responding ?
- The only one close, sir.
They can be here in four hours.
Four hours ?!
Thank you, Bride.
My God... !
(crewmen yelling out orders)
Sir !
We are swung out and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women
and children into the boats, sir ?
Yes, we...
Sir ?
Women and children first.
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please !
Step this way, please ! That's right.
Come towards me !
Thank you.
Good.
For the time being l shall require
only women and children.
Right here.
Like the Captain said,...
..nice and cheery
so there's no panic.
''Wedding Dance.''
Lifebelts on !
Put your lifebelts on !
Here, put your lifebelt on.
Here, come on...
lt isn't time to go up
to the boats yet.
Please stay calm.
Look, please make sure
you've got your lifebelts on.
Women and children to the front.
What are we doing, Mummy ?
When the first-class people
are in the boats, they'll start with us...
..and we'll want to be ready.
(men arguing)
Go and get some help.
Lower away ! Left and right together !
Steady !
Both sides together !
Stop ! Stop !
(screaming)
Hold the left side !
Right side only ! Right side only !
Right side only !
Hold the left side !
Right side down !
Lower away together !
Steady, lads !
You know, l do believe this ship may sink.
l've been asked to give you this
small token of our appreciation.
Compliments of Mr Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister, you heard the man.
lnto the boat.
- Any room for a gentleman, gentlemen ?
- Only women at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be seated
according to class ?
l hope they're not too crowded.
Oh, Mother... Shut up !
Don't you understand ?!
The water is freezing and there aren't
enough boats ! Not enough by half.
Half the people on this ship
are going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First-class seats are right up here.
lt's a pity l didn't keep that drawing.
lt'll be worth more by morning.
(Crewman) Women and children
towards the front.
You unimaginable bastard.
(Molly) Come on, Rose, darling.
There's plenty of room for you.
- Come on, Rose. You're next.
- Come into the boat, Rose.
(Cal) Come.
Rose !
Get into the boat !
Rose...
Goodbye, Mother.
Rose ?
Where are you going ?
To him ?!
To be a whore to a gutter rat ?!
l'd rather be his whore
than your wife !
No... No !
l said no !
(Ruth) Rose !
Please stop !
- And lower away !
- Rose !
- Man the tiller !
- No, wait !
Rose !
Hold the left side there !
Help !
Can anybody hear me !
Hello, help me !
Help me !
Help me ! Can anybody hear me !
Somebody help me !
Mr Andrews !
Check the starboard corridor.
Madam, please, put on a lifebelt.
Lucy, for God's sake, put on
your lifebelt. Set a good example.
Anyone in here ?
Mr Andrews, thank God ! Where would
they take someone under arrest ?
You have to get to a boat right away.
l'm doing this with or without your help,
but without will take longer.
Take the elevator to the very bottom.
Go left down the crewmen's passage.
Go right and left again at the stairs.
You'll come to a corridor.
This could be bad.
(water gurgling)
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit !
Excuse me !
- (Crewman) The lifts are closed.
- l do not care...
The lifts are...
l'm sorry, miss,
but the lifts are closed.
l'm through being polite,
goddamn it ! Now take me down !
''E'' deck.
Come on... Come on, come on...
l'm going back up !
No !
No ! No !
Miss, wait !
Come back ! l'm going back up !
l'm going back up !
Crew passage...
Crew passage.
Jack !
Rose !
Rose, l'm in here !
- l'm in here !
- Jack !
l'm in here !
- Rose !
Jack ! Jack !
l'm sorry !
l'm sorry ! l'm so sorry !
- Lovejoy put it in my pocket.
- l know ! l know, l know, l know !
Rose, you have to find
a spare key, all right ?
Look in that cabinet.
lt's a little silver one, Rose.
Silver...
These are all brass !
Check right here, Rose.
Rose...
How did you find out l didn't do it ?
l didn't.
l just realised l already knew.
Keep looking !
No key.
- There's no key !
- Rose, listen.
You have to go find help.
lt'll be all right.
l'll be right back.
l'll just wait here.
Hello, is there anyone here ?
Hello ?
ls there anybody down here ?
We need help ! Hello !
Damn it !
Can anybody hear me ! Please !
Hello ! Hello !
Oh, thank God !
l need your help. There's a man
back here and... Wait !
Hello ?
(loud rumbling)
(panting)
Hello ?
- Miss, you shouldn't be here now.
- Please, l need your help.
There is a man down here
and he is trapped !
- No need to panic.
- l'm not panicking !
You're going the wrong way !
Let go of me ! Listen !
To hell with you.
(ship creaking)
(crewman shouting orders)
Lower away !
Oh, God...
Oh, my God...
(gasps)
Jack !
Rose !
Will this work ?
l guess we'll find out. Come on.
Wait, wait, wait, wait !
Try some practice swings.
Good. Try to hit the same mark
again, Rose. You can do it.
Okay. That's enough practice.
Come on, Rose. You can do it.
Listen, just hit it really hard
and really fast.
Wait ! Open your hands up
a little more.
- Like that ?
- Right.
Listen, Rose... l trust you.
Go !
You did it !
Come on, let's go !
Oh, shit, this is cold ! Oh, shit !
Shit ! Shit !
This is the way out.
We have to find another way. Come on.
Pull !
(orchestra playing)
Put your backs into it ! Pull !
Pull !
Now there's something
you don't see every day.
What's this luggage doing here ?
Get rid of it ! We need the room !
(crewman giving orders)
Keep calm !
Move along there. Make more room.
That's right. Look sharp.
- Lovejoy !
- She's not on the starboard side.
We're running out of time and this
martinet isn't letting any men on.
There's one on the other side
letting men on.
Then that's our play. We'll need
some insurance first. Come on.
(banging)
This way. All the way down here.
Here ! What do you think you're doing ?
You'll have to pay for that !
That's White Star Line property !
Shut up !
Will you hold the boat a moment ?
l just have to run back to my room...
Sit down !
Mr Lightoller, why are the boats
being launched half full ?
- Not now, Mr Andrews.
- 20 or so in a boat built for 65...
..and l saw one boat with only 12 ! 12 !
We weren't sure of the weight,
Mr Andrews. These boats may buckle.
Rubbish !
They were tested in Belfast
with 70 men !
Now fill these boats, Mr Lightoller,
for God's sake, man !
l need more women and children, please !
(Crewman) Get back in there.
This is not an exit.
- Get back in there.
- This is not an exit !
You can't keep us locked in here !
The ship's bloody sinking !
Bring forward the women !
Unlock the gates.
Women only !
No men !
(yelling)
Get back !
Lock the gates !
Get them back from those gates !
Don't touch the gates !
There are women and children
down here !
Let us up so we can have a chance !
Get back !
- Jack !
- Tommy !
- Can we get out ?
- lt's hopeless that way !
Whatever we do,
we've gotta do it fast.
Jack !
Fabrizio !
The boats are all gone.
- This whole place is flooding.
- There is niente this way.
All right. Let's go this way. Come on.
l make my own luck.
So do l.
Come on !
No, come on. Let's go this way.
(speaking Arabic)
This way !
Go back to the main stairwell
and everything will be sorted out there.
The hell it will !
lt will get sorted out back there.
Go back to the main stairwell.
- Open the gate.
- Go back...
- Open the gate now !
- Go back down the main stairwell !
Goddamn it ! Son of a bitch !
Open the damn gate !
Go back !
- Fabri, Tommy. Give me a hand here !
- Move aside ! Move aside !
Pull !
- Move aside !
- Put that down !
Move aside !
- One ! Two !
- Stop that !
Three !
Again !
Let's go !
Let's go, Rose.
You can't go up there !
You can't do this !
(Lightoller) Keep order ! Keep order here !
Back ! Back ! Back !
(screaming)
Hold on to her !
Pull her in !
Get back, l say !
Or l'll shoot you all like dogs !
Keep order here !
Keep order, l say.
Mr Lowe, man this boat.
(Lowe) ls everybody all right ?
Nobody panic.
(Crewman) Stay back !
- We're too late.
- There are more boats at the front.
Stay with this one.
Murdoch seems to be quite practical.
(women screaming)
(Lowe) Sit down !
Stay back, you lot.
Stay back ! Stay back,
the lot of you ! Stay back !
(gunshots)
lt's starting to fall apart.
We don't have much time.
Mr Murdoch ?
Mr Hockley...
You two, with me, now !
l'm a businessman, as you know,
and l've a business proposition for you.
(Crewman) Easy now ! All together !
Lower away ! Lower away !
(Jack) Come on, Rose.
The boats are gone !
Colonel, are there any boats
on that side ?
No, miss, but there are a couple
of boats all the way forward.
What's the use ?
Nobody's listening to us, anyway.
They don't listen to us at dinner, either.
Come on, let's play. Keep us warm.
''Orpheus''.
(playing fast music from
''Orpheus ln The Underworld'')
Music to drown by.
Now l know l'm in first class !
- Where is everyone ?
- They're all still aft, sir.
We have an understanding, then,
Mr Murdoch ?
(everyone shouting)
(gunshots)
Women and children only !
Get back ! Step back, sir.
Come through, madam.
This way. Step back, sir.
You better check the other side.
Go !
(Murdoch) Any more women
and children ? Any children ?
l found her on the other side
waiting for a boat.
With him.
- Any more women and children ?
- They're all aboard.
Anyone else, then !
- Anyone else !
- Hurry along.
Stand by the falls.
Oh, goddamn it all to hell !
Shit !
Fire !
Sir ! Sir, you can't go through here.
Sir, you can't go through.
Yes, yes, splendid. Right.
Right.
(Murdoch) Prepare to lower !
Ready on the left.
Take them down.
Keep it steady.
Both sides together. Steady...
Give her to me.
Daddy...
lt'll be fine, darling.
Don't you worry.
lt's goodbye for a little while.
Only a little while.
There's another boat for daddies.
This one's for mummies and children.
Hold mummy's hand and be a good girl.
- l'm not going without you.
- You have to... Now !
No, Jack.
- Get in the boat, Rose.
- No, Jack.
Get on the boat !
Yes, get on the boat, Rose.
My God, look at you.
You look a fright !
Here.
Put this on.
Come.
- Go on. l'll get the next one.
- No ! Not without you !
l'll be fine. l'm a survivor, all right ?
Don't worry about me.
Now go on, get on.
l have an arrangement
with an officer on the ship.
Jack and l can get off safely.
See ?
- Got my own boat to catch.
- Hurry !
They're almost full.
Step aboard, miss.
Step aboard, please.
(Crewman)
Keep back. Keep back, l say !
Clear the row, please.
Lower away !
(Crewman) Slowly...
Keep going, keep going.
And lower away evenly, lads.
Easy... Lower away.
You're a good liar.
Almost as good as you.
(Crewman) Easy now... and lower away.
There's no, uh...
There's no arrangement, is there ?
No, there is.
Not that you'll benefit much from it.
l always win, Jack.
One way or another.
(Crewman) Easy...
Even, lads.
Keep going, keep going.
Rose !
(passengers yelling)
- Stop her !
- What are you doing !
Stop her !
No !
Rose !
You're so stupid ! Why'd you do that ?
You're so stupid, Rose !
Why did you do that ? Why ?
You jump, l jump, right ?
Right.
Oh, God, l couldn't go.
l couldn't go, Jack.
lt's all right.
We'll think of something.
(Rose) At least l'm with you.
Come on !
Come on ! Move !
Move !
Come on, Rose. Come on.
(gunshot)
Rose, come on !
Move, Rose !
Go !
(creaking)
l hope you enjoy your time together !
(laughter)
What could possibly be funny ?
l put the diamond in the coat...
..and l put the coat on her !
Come on !
(child crying)
(wailing)
We can't leave him.
All right, come on !
Go back !
(yelling in Czech)
lt's the wrong way ! Come back !
Go !
Jack !
Rose !
This way !
Come on.
Give me your hand.
Oh, God !
Help !
(Rose) Help !
- Wait, sir ! Open the gate, please !
- Help us, please !
Help us !
Please !
Bloody hell !
Hurry !
Come on ! Come on !
- Go !
- Jesus...
- Please !
- Come on !
Hurry !
Come on !
l'm sorry, l dropped the keys !
Wait ! Please !
Don't leave ! Please ! Get more help !
l got 'em ! Which one is it, Rose ?
The sharp one, try the sharp one.
Hurry, Jack.
Oh, no !
lt's stuck !
Hurry, Jack !
l got it ! l got it ! Go ! Go, Rose !
Go ! Go !
Jack !
Jack ! Come on !
Move ! Move !
(Crewman) Keep on rocking !
Oars in place ! Get an oar under it !
Women and children only, damn you !
(Crewman) Hold it ! Hold it !
(men yelling)
Get these davits cranked in !
Then get the falls hooked up !
(Murdoch) Stay back !
Mommy... !
Keep going up !
(Murdoch) Stop pushing !
Stay back !
Give us a chance to live,
you limey bastard !
l'll shoot any man
who tries to get past me !
Bastard !
Get back !
We had a deal, damn you.
Your money can't save you
any more than it can save me.
Get back !
(Crewman) Women and children only !
(gunshot)
(screaming)
No ! Tommy...
Bastardo !
Oh, no ! Oh, no... !
Oh, no... ! Tommy... !
No !
Stand back, damn you !
(screaming)
(child crying)
l have a child !
- l have a child !
- Clear a path here !
Please, l have a child !
Please, l'm all she has in the world.
Go on.
Step back !
Here, give her to me.
Give her here.
(child wailing)
There, there.
Wait, wait, wait.
Mr Andrews...
Rose.
Won't you even make a try for it ?
l'm sorry that l didn't build you
a stronger ship, young Rose.
lt's going fast.
We have to move.
Wait.
Good luck to you, Rose.
And to you.
Mr Guggenheim...
These are for you, Mr Guggenheim.
No, thank you.
We are dressed in our best and
are prepared to go down as gentlemen.
But we would like a brandy.
Capitan.
Capitan, where should l go ?
Please...
(Crewman) Captain !
Captain... Sir.
(orchestra still playing)
Right... That's it, then.
Goodbye, Wally. Good luck.
So long, old chap.
(starts playing
''Nearer My God To Thee'')
And so they lived happily together
for 300 years...
..in the land of Tir Na Nog.
Land of eternal youth and beauty.
There's no time !
Cut those falls !
Cut 'em ! Cut 'em if you have to !
l need a knife ! l need a knife !
Cut her loose !
Cut those bloody falls !
Gentlemen, it has been a privilege
playing with you tonight.
We have to stay on the ship
as long as possible ! Come on !
(Jack) This way. Over the rail !
Come on, Rose. Jump !
Come on !
(screaming)
(gasping)
(Jack) l got you. Jump !
l've got you, miss !
Jack !
(Cal) Get back !
(cables snapping)
(metal groaning)
No ! You'll swamp us !
(screaming)
Though l walk through
the valley of the shadow of death...
You wanna walk a little faster
through that valley ?!
Row !
Pull together !
(screams)
Holy Mary, Mother of God,...
..pray for us sinners now
and at the hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace...
This way.
Come on !
l saw a new heaven and a new earth...
..when the first heaven and
the first earth had passed away...
..and there was no more sea.
lt'll be over soon.
lt'll all be over soon.
And he shall dwell with them
and they shall be his people...
..and God himself shall be with them.
Jack,...
..this is where we first met.
And God shall wipe away
all the tears from their eyes.
And there shall be no more death.
Neither shall there be sorrow or crying.
Neither shall there be
any more pain...
..for the former world has passed away.
Bloody pull faster, and pull !
(screaming)
Hang on, Miss Trudy !
(glass shattering)
(screams)
(Man) Help me ! Please, save me !
(Woman) Help !
(Jack) Hold on real tight !
(distant screaming)
(woman sobbing)
God Almighty !
(Crewman) Get those breakers in !
Keep 'em in !
(crackling)
(screams)
(people screaming)
(ship creaking)
(planks splitting)
(everyone screaming)
We have to move !
Give me your hand.
l'll pull you over.
Give me your hand !
l've got you. l won't let go.
Come on, l've got you !
- What's happening, Jack ?
- l don't know !
- Hold on !
- Jack !
(Man) Help me, please !
Someone help me !
(people screaming)
(panting)
(screams)
(Woman) Please help ! Help !
This is it !
(Rose) Oh, God ! Oh, God !
Hold on !
Oh, God ! Oh...
The ship is gonna suck us down.
Take a deep breath when l say.
Kick for the surface
and keep kicking.
Do not let go of my hand.
We're gonna make it, Rose. Trust me.
l trust you.
Ready ? Ready ?
Now !
(screaming)
Jack ! Jack !
Jack !
(everyone screaming)
Jack ! Jack !
No !
Jack !
Rose !
Get off her ! Get off her !
- Rose !
- Jack !
Swim, Rose ! l need you to swim !
Keep swimming !
- lt's so cold !
- Swim, Rose !
Come on... here...
Keep swimming... come on.
Here, get on it.
Get on top.
Come on, Rose.
Stay on it, Rose.
Jack...
You'll be all right now.
(whistle blows)
(whistle)
(Crewman) Return...
..the boats !
The boats are coming back for us, Rose.
Hold on just a bit longer.
They... had to row away
from the suction...
..but... now they'll be coming back.
(Woman) Come back !
- For God's sake !
- Please ! Help us !
(faint cries in distance)
Come back ! For God's sake !
You don't understand. lf we go back,
they'll swamp the boat !
- They'll pull us right down !
- Knock it off. You're scaring me.
Come on, girls, grab an oar.
Are you mad ?! We're in the middle
of the North Atlantic !
Do you people want to live
or do you want to die !
l don't understand a one of you.
What's the matter with you ?!
lt's your men out there !
- There's plenty of room for more.
- There'll be one less on this boat...
..if you don't shut that hole
in your face !
(woman in distance) Come back !
Take this one.
Bring in your oars over there.
Tie these two boats together as well.
Now make sure that's tied up
nice and tight.
Listen to me, men,
we have to go back.
l want to transfer all the women
from this boat into that boat.
Let's get some space there.
(distant moaning)
(shivering)
lt's getting quiet.
lt's just gonna take 'em
a couple of minutes to get...
..the boats organised.
l don't know about you, but...
..l intend to write a strongly worded letter
to the White Star Line...
..about all this.
(distant moans and cries for help)
l love you, Jack.
Don't you do that.
Don't you say your goodbyes. Not yet.
Do you understand me ?
l'm so cold.
Listen, Rose...
You're gonna get out of here.
You're gonna go on, and you're
gonna make lots of babies,...
..and you're gonna watch 'em grow.
You're gonna die an old...
..an old lady warm in her bed.
Not here.
Not this night. Not like this.
Do you understand me ?
l can't feel my body.
Winning that ticket was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
lt brought me to you...
..and l'm thankful for that, Rose.
l'm thankful.
You must... You must...
You must do me this honour...
You must promise me
that you'll survive,...
..that you won't give up,...
..no matter what happens,...
..no matter how hopeless.
Promise me now, Rose,...
..and never let go of that promise.
l promise.
Never let go.
l will never let go, Jack.
l'll never let go.
(Crewman) Right ahead, sir.
(Lowe) Oars !
Do you see any moving ?
No, sir. None moving, sir.
Check them.
Bring that oar up here.
Check them. Make sure.
These are dead, sir.
Now give way.
Ahead easy.
Careful with your oars.
Don't hit them.
ls there anyone alive out there !
Can anyone hear me ?
We waited too long.
We'll, keep checking them !
Keep looking !
ls there anyone alive out there !
Can anyone hear me !
(Rose singing softly)
#And it's up she goes.
# Up she goes.
(continues singing)
(Lowe's voice, garbled and slow)
Jack ?
Jack.
Jack... there's a boat.
Jack...
Jack ?
Jack !
There's a boat, Jack.
Jack ?
Come back.
Come back !
(voices of searchers)
Come back ! Come back !
Hello !
Can anyone hear me !
There's nothing here, sir.
Come back !
Come back...
l'll never let go.
l promise.
(whistling)
Come about !
1,500 people went into the sea
when Titanic sank from under us.
There were 20 boats
floating nearby...
..and only one came back.
One.
Six were saved from the water,...
..myself included.
Six... out of 1,500.
Afterward,..
..the 700 people in the boats
had nothing to do but wait.
Wait to die, wait to live...
Wait for an absolution...
..that would never come.
Sir, l don't think you'll find
any of your people down here.
lt's all steerage.
(Woman) His hair is reddish brown.
Reddish brown and a white beard.
- ls there another passenger list ?
- There's no other list.
- Perhaps he's on another ship.
- We're doing all we can, ma'am.
(Rose)
That's the last time l ever saw him.
He married, of course,
and inherited his millions.
But the crash of '29
hit his interests hard...
..and he put a pistol
in his mouth that year.
Or so l read.
Can l take your name, please, love ?
Dawson.
Rose Dawson.
Thank you.
We never found anything on Jack.
There's no record of him at all.
No, there wouldn't be, would there ?
And l've never spoken of him until now.
Not to anyone.
Not even your grandfather.
A woman's heart
is a deep ocean of secrets.
But now you know there was
a man named Jack Dawson...
..and that he saved me.
ln every way that a person can be saved.
l don't even have a picture of him.
He exists now only in my memory.
(Man) Keldysh, Keldysh,
Mir 2 on our way to the surface.
(Brock) l was saving this
for when l found the diamond.
l'm sorry.
Three years l've thought
of nothing except Titanic...
..but l never got it.
l never let it in.
# Every night in my dreams...
# ..l see you,...
# ..l feel you...
# That is how l know you go on.
# Far across the distance...
#And spaces between us...
# You have come to show you go on.
# Near...
# Far...
#Wherever you are...
# l believe that the heart does go on.
# Once more...
# ..you open the door...
# ..and you're here in my heart,...
# ..and my heart will go on and on.
# Love can touch just one time...
# ..and last for a lifetime...
# ..and never let go till we're gone.
# Love was when l loved you...
# One true time l hold to...
# ln my life we'll always go on.
# Near...
# Far...
#Wherever you are...
# l believe that the heart does go on.
# Once more...
# ..you open the door...
# ..and you're here in my heart,...
# ..and my heart will go on and on.
# You're here...
# There's nothing l fear...
#And l know that my heart will go on.
#We'll stay...
# ..forever this way...
# You are safe in my heart...
# ..and my heart will go on and on.